Guide to the Emma Goldman Papers, 1909-1941 and undated RL.11353
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Letters, 1909-1941 and undated; 1
  - Emma Goldman (The Hague, Netherlands) to Tom [Keell] (n.p.), 1933 January 23; 1 Leaves; 2 pages; 26 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Goldman informs Keell of her travel plans for England. She then comments on one of her attackers in the movement and informs Keell of the death of comrade Maria Goldsmith. In a postscript she notes the high price of the British edition of her autobiography, and comments on Rebecca West, an English contact.
    Anarchists; Autobiographies; Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940; Keell, Thomas H.
  - Emma Goldman (London, England) to Tom [Keell] (n.p.), 1933 March 9; 2 Leaves; 2 pages; 26 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Goldman comments on several meetings held in London, and outlines more meetings in the future. She then comments on the Anti War Congress held by the Communists.
    Anarchism -- England; Communism -- England; Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940; Keell, Thomas H.
  - Emma Goldman (St. Tropez, France) to Tom [Keell] (n.p.), 1933 September 22; 1 Leaves; 1 page; 27 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Goldman outlines her travel plans, with a possible return to England rather than to Canada. She requests his suggestions for reaching the non-Communist members of the Labour movement. She then comments on her failure to make money in other endeavors.
    Labour Party (Great Britain); Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940; Keell, Thomas H.
  - Emma Goldman (S.S. Ascania Cunard Line) to Tom [Keell] (n.p.), 1933 December 8; 2 Leaves; 2 pages; 25 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Goldman reports that she was kicked out of Holland following her third lecture, and since nothing was planning in England, she is now on her way to Canada. She reports that she has low expectations for the trip, but there is a possibility of a visa for the United States. She requests that Keell send literature for her to sell at her lectures.
  - Emma Goldman (Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania) to Evelyn Metcalfe (Saratoga Springs, New York), 1934 April 11; 2 Leaves; 2 pages; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Goldman discusses her plans to visit Metcalfe, and the failure of her tour in the United States.
    Anarchism -- United States; Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940
  - Emma Goldman (Rochester, New York) to Thomas Lavers (Bristol, England), 1934 April 15; 4 Leaves; 4 pages; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Goldman discusses her United States tour and its possible extension, the effect the tour has had upon her, and its mismanagement. She mentions meeting a anarchist from Chicago, Frank Heiner.
  - [Emma Goldman] (Montreal, Canada) to "Comrade" (n.p.), 1934 May 11; 1 Leaves; 1 page; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Goldman reports on her tour, the raising of money for Russian political prisoners, and successful publicity and contacts made. She hopes for an extended visa for another trip to the United States.
  - Emma Goldman (Toronto?, Canada) to Thomas H. Keell (Stroud, England), 1934 May 24; 2 Leaves; 2 pages; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Goldman discusses the successes and failures of her tour, then requests that Keell go about purchasing the sheets for Berkman's prison memoir.
    Anarchism -- United States; Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940; Keell, Thomas H.
  - Emma Goldman (Toronto, Canada) to Thomas [H.] Keell (Stroud, England), 1934 August 1; 2 Leaves; 2 pages; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Goldman discusses obtaining discounted copies of Berkman's prison memoirs or purchasing the plates for the work. She then outlines her unsettled plans for touring in Europe, America, or Canada, and the lack of advancement in anarchist ideas. She closes by discussing the death of Erich Muhsam.
    Anarchism; Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940; Keell, Thomas H.; Mühsam, Erich, 1878-1934
  - Emma Goldman (Toronto, Canada) to Tom [Keell] (n.p.), 1934 September 4; 1 Leaves; 1 page; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Goldman requests literature to be sent for sale at her lectures, along with a settling of accounts. She closes by discussing the death of [John?] Turner.
  - Emma Goldman (Toronto, Canada) to Thomas H. Keell (Stroud, England), 1934 October 6; 2 Leaves; 2 pages; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Goldman discusses her failure to raise any money, and her hesitancy to purchase the copies of Berkman's memoirs. In addition, she laments the lack of good organizers and writers in the United States. She lists the articles she will soon publish.
  - [Emma Goldman] (Toronto, Canada) to B. Yelensky (Chicago, Illinois), 1934 October 31; 3 Leaves; 3 pages; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Goldman writes that she has been forced to drop the project of republishing Berkman's book in the United States, and that she will stay in Canada until the Spring, trying to earn some money. She then outlines how money should be collected in support of the Spanish Revolution and the role of the intelligentsia in the anarchist movement.
    Spain -- Politics and government -- 1931-1939; Anarchism; Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940
  - Emma Goldman (Montreal, Canada) to Thomas H. Keell (Stroud, England), 1934 November 27; 1 Leaves; 1 page; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Goldman writes that her tour has not been as successful as the last time she was in Montreal. One reason has been the reactionary stance of the local government, another the glamor of Bolshevik ideas. She writes of her plans for the tour, and a return to America or France in the Spring.
  - Emma Goldman (Montreal, Canada) to Joseph Ishill (Berkeley Heights, New Jersey), 1934 November 29; 1 Leaves; 2 pages; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Goldman writes about her lack of help with her tour, her work with anarchist youth, and the backwardness in ideas in Canada. She comments on Ishill's work on William Morris and Votairine de Clayre. She hopes to visit Ishill during an American tour.
    Anarchism -- Canada; Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940; Ishill, Joseph.; Morris, William, 1834-1896; De Cleyre, Voltairine, 1866-1912
  - [Emma Goldman, Montreal, Canada] to Jeanne Levey (Chicago, Illinois), 1934 December 10; 2 Leaves; 3 pages; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Goldman discusses her apartment, her plans for a 10-lecture tour, the assistance she is receiving, and how she must fight Communist and Fascist ideas. In a postscript she discusses her articles in Harpers.
    Anarchism -- Canada; Communism; Fascism; Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940
  - Emma Goldman (Montreal, Canada) to Tom Keell (Stroud, England), 1934 December 19; 1 Leaves; 1 page; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Goldman notes that she has returned pamphlets rather than have them confiscated. She comments on London Freedom, and the death of a mutual comrade, "Charles."
    Anarchism -- Periodicals; Freedom (London, England: 1886); Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940; Keell, Thomas H.
  - Emma Goldman (n.p.) to Comrade, [1934?]; 2 Leaves; 2 pages; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Goldman compares Marinus van der Lubbe's association with the Reichstag fire and Alexander Berkman's Frick assassination attempt. She then discusses Anarcho-Syndicalist theory. She comments on growing anti-war feeling among the youth. Page 2 of the letter is missing.
    Anarchism; Syndicalism; Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940; Lubbe, Marinus van der, 1909-1934; Berkman, Alexander, 1870-1936
  - Emma Goldman (S.S. Ascania Cunard Line) to Thomas H. Keell (Stroud, England), 1935 May 14; 1 Leaves; 1 page; 16 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Goldman briefly outlines her plans once she returns to France.
  - Emma Goldman (Paris, France) to Tom [Keell] (n.p.), 1935 October 27; 1 Leaves; 1 page; 27 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Goldman comments about the postponement of her lectures in England, along with plans for copies to be produced of the Berkman memoir.
  - Emma Goldman (London, England) to Thomas H. Keell (Stroud, England), 1935 November 16; 1 Leaves; 2 pages; 9 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    In a postcard, Goldman requests some bound copies of Berkman's memoirs to place on sale at her lectures.
  - Emma Goldman (London, England) to Tom [Keell] (n.p.), 1935 November 23; 1 Leaves; 1 page; 25 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Goldman objects to the "commercial tone" of Keell's recent letter, noting that she will settle the account for the copies of Berkman's memoirs.
  - Emma Goldman (London, England) to Thomas H. Keell (Stroud, England), 1935 December 19; 1 Leaves; 1 page; 9 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Goldman comments on the difficulty of finding a publisher for a German work Berkman has been translating.
    Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940; Keell, Thomas H.; Berkman, Alexander, 1870-1936
  - Emma Goldman (London?, England) to Harry [Kelly?] (n.p.), 1936 January 2; 2 Leaves; 3 pages; 25 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Goldman writes that Berkman has celebrated his sixty-fifth birthday. She requests that Harry send the money owed Berkman, commenting on their poverty and difficulty in raising money. She is more positive that this lecture tour will yield positive results, and especially excited to speak with the youth at the National Labor Colleges in South Wales. She desires most of all to gain ground for the anarchist movement in England.
    Anarchism -- England; Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940; Kelly, Harry, 1871-1953; Berkman, Alexander, 1870-1936
  - Emma Goldman (London, England) to Tom [Keell] (n.p.), 1936 January 9; 1 Leaves; 2 pages; 25 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Goldman comments on possible work for Berkman, her general busyness, the literature for her lectures, and completed payment for the Berkman memoirs.
  - Emma Goldman (London?, England) to Tom [Keell] (n.p.), 1936 February 6; 2 Leaves; 3 pages; 25 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Goldman writes that her current lecture tour has failed, but she has plans for more lectures in the Fall. She requests more literature, then comments on the cost of shipping the Berkman memoir to the United States and Canada.
  - Emma Goldman (London, England) to Tom [Keell] (n.p.), 1936 March 1; 3 Leaves; 3 pages; 27 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Goldman comments on the progress of her work in Plymouth and her upcoming lectures, for which she requests some literature. She then reports that Berkman has been hospitalized and therefore she wants to make a profit, if possible, on the sale of his memoir.
    Anarchism -- England; Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940; Keell, Thomas H.; Berkman, Alexander, 1870-1936
  - Emma Goldman (n.p.) to Tom [Keell] (n.p.), 1936 March 9; 1 Leaves; 2 pages; 27 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Goldman writes about her schedule for lectures, then comments on a contact for the Labor Colleges in London. She describes how she almost succumbed to carbon monoxide poisoning.
  - Emma Goldman (London, England) to Tom [Keell] (n.p.), 1936 March 11; 1 Leaves; 1 page; 27 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Goldman requests literature written by her for her lectures.
  - Emma Goldman (London, England) to Tom [Keell] (n.p.), 1936 April 2; 1 Leaves; 2 pages; 27 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Goldman writes of the success of her recent lectures. She adds that Alexander Berkman has undergone a second surgery and is recovering. She will return to France as soon as possible, but adds that with the possibility of war it is "downright stupid to make plans."
  - Emma Goldman (n.p.) to Tom [Keell] (n.p.), 1936 April 3?; 1 Leaves; 2 pages; 20 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Goldman settles her accounts, and asks if Alexander Berkman is due any more money for his memoirs. She plans to leave for France immediately and asks Keell about their contact for the Labor Colleges in London.
  - Emma Goldman (Nice, France) to Thomas H. Keell (Stroud, England), 1936 April 8; 1 Leaves; 1 page; 10 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    In a postcard, Goldman reports on Alexander Berkman's condition.
  - Emma Goldman (Nice, France) to Thomas H. Keell (Stroud, England), 1936 April 1; 1 Leaves; 2 pages; 10 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    In a postcard, Goldman provides an update on Alexander Berkman's improved condition.
  - Emma Goldman (Nice, France) to Thomas H. Keell (Stroud, England), 1936 April 21?; 1 Leaves; 1 page; 10 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    In a postcard, Goldman discusses money due for Alexander Berkman's memoir, then provides an update on Berkman's condition.
  - Emma Goldman (Nice, France) to E. C. Carbo, 1936 May 1; 4 Leaves; 4 pages; 27 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Goldman answers a questionnaire regarding Anarchist principles, sent for Alexander Berkman. She writes about Anarchist participation in elections, power during the revolutionary transition period, solidarity with the workers, and various situations in Spain.
  - Emma Goldman (Nice, France) to Tom [Keell] (n.p), 1936 May 12; 2 Leaves; 3 pages; 27 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Goldman provides an update on Alexander Berkman's condition, and the condition of Emmy, Berkman's girlfriend. She comments on her recent letter to the comrades in Spain and the disappearance of Erich Muhsam's widow, then outlines the current plans for her next speaking tour in England.
  - Emma Goldman (Nice, France) to Thomas H. Keell (Stroud, England), 1936 June 30; 1 Leaves; 1 page; 10 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    In a postcard, Goldman announces Alexander Berkman's death, and her plans to return to St. Tropez.
  - Emma Goldman (London, England) to Harry [Kelly?] (n.p.), 1937 June 7; 2 Leaves; 2 pages; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Goldman writes that her work with Spain is finished, but she worries about events there, because she can get no direct word from participants.She argues that she may have to drop her membership in the CNT-FAI. She comments on a possible visa for the United States, then on Errico Malatesta's activities in Spain.
    Spain -- Politics and government -- 1931-1939; Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940; Kelly, Harry, 1871-1953; Malatesta, Errico, 1853-1932
  - Emma Goldman (Marseille, France) to T. H. Keell (Stroud, England), 1937 September 14; 1 Leaves; 1 page; 9 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Goldman writes that she is en route to Barcelona and "it means going into the cage of mad days."
    Spain -- Politics and government -- 1931-1939; Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940; Keell, Thomas H.
  - Emma Goldman (London, England) to "Dear friend", 1938 February 10; 1 Leaves; 1 page; 25 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    In an open letter, Goldman announces an opening of an English office for the International Anti-Fascist Solidarity (S.I.A.), and its plans to support refugees in Catalonia.
    Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940; Solidaridad Internacional Antifascista
  - Emma Goldman (London, England) to Harry [Kelly?] (n.p.), 1938 April 28; 2 Leaves; 3 pages; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Goldman writes about her ill-fated attempts to raise money for her comrades in Spain, and the general indifference to the plight of people there. She contrasts this with the emotional letters she receives from Spain, which inspire her to keep working. She reports on plans to develop a committee to work on obtaining a visa for her to visit the United States, although she plans to go to Canada.
    Spain -- Politics and government -- 1931-1939; Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940; Kelly, Harry, 1871-1953
  - Emma Goldman (Toronto, Canada) to C.V. (n.p.), 1939 May 30; 2 Leaves; 2 pages; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Goldman charges her rejuvenated spirit to her work in Spain. She discusses the reproduction of clippings and writing a message for the comrades in the West.
    Spain -- Politics and government -- 1931-1939; Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940
  - Emma Goldman (Toronto, Canada) to Harry Kelly (New Rochelle, New York), 1939 May 31; 1 Leaves; 2 pages; 8 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    In a postcard, Goldman mentions a wire she sent that has gone awry, and being remembered by her friends. She also requests the loan of books.
    Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940; Kelly, Harry, 1871-1953
  - Emma Goldman (Toronto, Canada) to Harry [Kelly?] (n.p.), 1939 June 14; 1 Leaves; 2 pages; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Goldman notes the potential for some lectures in Winnipeg. She comments on the help of a good friend, Harry's unemployment, and that they have been compelled to act on their ideas, whether successful or not. She also comments on the "Stalin criminals" and their activities in Spain and France.
    Anarchism -- Canada; Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940; Kelly, Harry, 1871-1953
  - Emma Goldman (Toronto, Canada) to Harry [Kelly?] (n.p.), 1939 July 9; 1 Leaves; 2 pages; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Goldman outlines the various ways she has been celebrating her 70th birthday, and of her plans to celebrate the 50th anniversary of pledging herself to anarchism.
  - [Emma Goldman] to unknown, 1938?; 1 Leaves; 1 page; 27 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Page 2 of unidentified letter. Goldman discusses efforts to support the transportation of Spanish comrades to Mexico, and comments on working with Communists and on [Juan?] Negrin.
    Anarchism -- Spain; Communists -- Spain; Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940
  - Emma Goldman (n.p.) to J. B. Moore (Philadelphia, Pennsylvania), undated; 1 Leaves; 1 page; 14 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    In a copy of a telegram, Goldman writes that a Jewish meeting may not be announced before an English meeting.
  - Maurice A. Hanline (n.p.) to Emma Goldman, 1929 June 5; 1 Leaves; 1 page (2 copies); 27 cm (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Hanline, who was vice president at publishing firm Horace LIveright, praises Goldman's autobiography, stating that he has instructed that an advance be offered for the work.
    Autobiographies; Hanline, Maurice A; Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940
  - Thomas H. Keell (London, England) to Emma Goldman (n.p.), 1927 July 15; 1 Leaves; 1 page; 25 cm (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Keell provides a statement of accounts and payments made, and notes an outstanding balance.
    Keell, Thomas H.; Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940
  - C. Edwards (London?, England) to "Dear Comrade", 1938 January 26; 1 Leaves; 1 page; 25 cm (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Edwards sent this letter on behalf of the Emma Goldman Lecture Committee, to solicit funds in support of public meetings to be held by Emma Goldman in London.
    Anarchism -- England; Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940
  - Harry Kelly (New Rochelle, New York) to Emma Goldman (n.p.), 1939 June 3; 1 Leaves; 1 page; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Kelly mentions that he received and read aloud her wire. He outlines possible books for Goldman to read.
    Kelly, Harry, 1871-1953; Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940
  - Ma[nnie?] (?, Conn.?) to Harry [Kelly] (n.p.), 1939 July 22; 2 Leaves; 2 pages; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Ma[nnie] discusses dinners to be held in honor of Emma Goldman's 50th anniversary as an anarchist. He prefers the dinners be held with her present. He would prefer to work for a dinner for Leonard [?].
  - H. Lynch (Toronto, Canada) to Emma Goldman (Toronto, Canada), 1927 January 25; 2 Leaves; 2 pages; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Lynch writes regarding arrangements for a debate between Goldman and Mr. Silver, a representative of the Socialist Labor Party.
  - A. [Alexander M.] Shapiro (Stockholm, Sweden) to [Thomas H.] Keell (n.p.), 1922 January 9; 2 Leaves; 3 pages; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Shapiro writes that his address in Moscow is blockaded, regarding misinformation about Russia in the press, including the fate of Russian political prisoners, especially those on hunger strikes. He plans to return to Russia if permitted to do so. In the meantime he wishes to catch up on the anarchist international movement and orders copies of Freedom from Keell.
    Political persecution -- Soviet Union -- History; Soviet Union -- Politics and government -- 1917-1936; Anarchism; Shapiro, Alexander M., 1882–1946; Keell, Thomas H.
  - A. [Alexander M.] Shapiro (Stockholm, Sweden) to [Thomas H.] Keell (n.p.), 1922 January 24; 2 Leaves; 3 pages; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Shapiro writes about ten anarchists shot in Russia and the various press coverage he will send to Keell. He also writes how he came to be in Sweden.
    Political persecution -- Soviet Union -- History; Shapiro, Alexander M., 1882–1946; Keell, Thomas H.
  - Sophie Kropotkin (Paris, France) to Miss Addams (n.p.), 1925 January 25; 1 Leaves; 1 page; 25 cm (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Kropotkin asks Addams to form a Peter Kropotkin Memorial Committee in the United States.
    Kropotkin, Petr Alekseevich, kniaz, 1842-1921
  - Antoinette F. Konikow (Boston, Massachusetts) to Comrade Swabeck (n.p.), 1926 August 24; 1 Leaves; 1 page; 23 cm (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Konikow writes to invite a speaker to Boston and comments on an "infernal plot" having to do with resolutions being considered.
    Socialism -- United States
  - John G. Wright (n.p.) to Comrade Swabeck (n.p.), 1930 June 18; 1 Leaves; 2 pages; 23 cm (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Wright urges immediate action in response to Stalinist transgressions.
  - Antoinette F. Konikow (Boston, Massachusetts) to Comrade Swabeck (n.p.), 1936 August 18; 1 Leaves; 2 pages; 23 cm (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Konikow makes a contribution to a monetary fund, and urges a meeting to protest "the infamous frame-up of Stalin," with coverage in the press, especially The Nation.
  - Antoinette F. Konikow (Boston, Massachusetts) to Comrade Swabeck (n.p.), 1936 August 19; 1 Leaves; 1 page; 23 cm (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Konikow makes a contribution to a fund, and seeks to arrange a meeting with Comrade Shachtman regarding the frame-up of Stalin.
  - No name (n.p.) to Antoinette F. Konikow (Boston, Massachusetts), 1936 August 22; 1 Leaves; 1 page; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Unidentified writer, perhaps Comrade Swabeck?, writes about the frame-up of Stalin, the planned statements regarding events, planning for the meeting with Shachtman, and publication of articles.
  - Antoinette F. Konikow (Boston, Massachusetts) to Comrade Swabeck (n.p.), 1936 November 19; 1 Leaves; 2 pages; 23 cm (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Konikow writes regarding a speaker for a Spanish meeting, adding that the Communist Party is organizing its own large meeting beforehand.
  - No name (n.p.) to Comrade Konikow (n.p.), 1936 November 27; 1 Leaves; 1 page; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Unidentified writer, perhaps Comrade Swabeck?, writes about possible speakers for Konikow's meeting on Spain.
  - Antoinette F. Konikow (Boston, Massachusetts) to Comrade Swabeck (n.p.), 1936 November 30; 1 Leaves; 1 page; 23 cm (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Konikow writes of the speakers she will contact for her meeting, then questions their endorsement of a publication.
  - Willy Winnick (n.p.) to Anne (n.p.), 1937; 3 Leaves; 6 pages; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Winnick describes in detail local meetings planned and held, and the dispute over the federated labor party resolution.
  - Antoinette F. Konikow (n.p.) to Comrade Swabeck (n.p.), 1937 January 20; 1 Leaves; 3 pages; 22 cm (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Konikow writes requesting clarification regarding a resolution on a federated labor party passed by a local Labor Party Caucus.
  - Willy Winnick (n.p.) to Anne (n.p.), 1937 January 21; 1 Leaves; 2 pages; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Winnick writes in detail about the disagreement regarding the resolution on a federated labor party, and requests a response.
  - No name (n.p.) to [Willy] Winnick (n.p.), 1937 January 22; 1 Leaves; 2 pages; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 13)
    The unidentified author discusses the struggle against the centrist Zamites and suggests there should be flexibility regarding the federated labor party question.
  - Irving S. Abrams, Emma Goldman Memorial Committee (Chicago, Illinois) to Comrade, 1941 February 4; 1 Leaves; 1 page; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Abrams writes to solicit funds for Goldman's funeral expenses, cemetery lot, monument, and caretaking for the grave.
  - M. E. Fitzgerald, Mother Earth Publishing Association (New York, New York) to Freedom Press (London, England), 1914 August 5; 1 Leaves; 1 page; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Fitzgerald writes regarding subscription fulfillment and ordering issues.She mentions the hunger strike of Rebecca Edelsohn, who protested against the United States becoming involved in a war with Mexico.
    Freedom Press (London, England); Edelsohn, Rebecca